hello in today's video i have a
secondary context past traversal
vulnerability
that was found in starbucks and allowed
to access
100 million customer records it was
found and reported by sam curry
who uses nickname zlz and he mentioned
some help from justin gartner
links to their profiles the report and
the blog post about this vulnerability
are in the description also you will
find there a link
to the presentation that some made about
this very topic
i highly recommend watching it but for
now
let's get to the explanation what's
important in case of this
past reversal vulnerability is that it
does not
affect any fire read or file upload
functionality
and to understand it let's see how
modern web applications work
and very trendy solution nowadays is
using microservices
it's an architecture where there is api
gateway
which talks with the user and in the
internal network
there are multiple services which talk
with the api gateway
and they are not reachable from the
internet
an api gateway basically takes the url
that user requests analyzes it
and sends the request to the appropriate
service
and what's important from the security
point of view
is that authentication and authorization
may happen
on api gateway level which means that
api gateway decides whether the user
has permissions to perform a specific
action
and whether to forward a specific
request to the service or not
and service does not really validate any
permissions
and another important thing that will be
key
to this vulnerability is that sometimes
user sends parameters in the url to the
api gateway
and it has to rewrite those parameters
when sending a request
to the appropriate service and starbucks
website
sends requests to the endpoints which
starts with
bff proxy and bff stands for
back-end for front-end and it's
basically a synonym
to the api gateway and the first
endpoint
that sam has tried is orchestra get user
but all the payloads that he sent return
a standard 404 page by standards 404
page
i mean the one returned by the api
gateway
when we see it we know that we are not
talking
to any service because if api gateway
would forward our request to a service
and the service would return 404 page
the response would look differently
so the hacker's next step was finding an
endpoint
that took parameters in the url
and rewritten those parameters while
making a request
to the service and this time
another 404 page was observed which
means
that it was coming from the backend
service
and the next step is sending enough
dot dot slash sequences to get 400
but request error and why is that
because dot dot slash sequence means
coming one directory back
and when we get bad request error it
means
that we have more dot dot slash
sequences
than the directories before in our path
and it basically allows us to determine
when we are at the start of the path
there was also one more obstacle namely
web application firewall blocked all
requests
that had more than one dot dot slash
sequence
but the researcher bypassed this
restriction
by putting a dot directory
between the dot slash sequences
dot directory basically means this
directory and in such context it
actually means
nothing it can easily be discarded or
used
to bypass web application firewall
so now the vulnerability is detected but
to actually exploit it
you need to know what to request and in
blackbox approach without access to the
documentation
or source code it's definitely not an
easy thing to do
you basically have to brute force the
valid urls
it's even more complicated if you have
to guess
multiple parts of the url and the server
doesn't give you any hint if you guessed
the first part right
in such case if you would take standard
word list
from dear search which has 6.5 000
words and you would like to brute force
two directories at a time
it suddenly becomes 43 million
combinations
however in this case if you would send a
request
to a valid path but without a trailing
slash
the application would redirect you to
the url
with the slash at the end it allowed to
brute force directories
one at a time and significantly reduce
the amount of requests
that you had to send to broadforce those
urls
and the endpoint which immediately
caught
researchers eyes was search v1 accounts
microsoft graph is a rest api for
multiple
microsoft services and search v1
accounts
happened out to be one of its endpoints
it was possible to query 100 million
customer records and get their personal
information
the researchers have decided to stop at
this point
and report the vulnerability even though
they knew
that there are multiple other endpoints
that could be even more impactful
than this one of course the
vulnerability was classified as critical
and the researchers got paid 4 thousand
dollars
which was at the time max for starbucks
back bounty program and that's it for
today's video
i hope you have learned something new if
you've enjoyed my
explanation leave a like and a
subscription down below
and for now i wish you happy hunting and
goodbye